WILLIAM MAYOR

FULL-STACK WEB ENGINEER, SYSTEMS ADMINISTRATOR

www.williammayor.co.uk jobs@williammayor.co.uk +447500222670

Technical

Python

HTML / CSS / Javascript

Git

PostgreSQL / MySQL OS X / Linux Knockout.js / Underscore.js / SASS Heroku / AWS TDD / Selenium

Docker / Vagrant

Profile

I'm a code monkey at heart; I love building solutions. I am a usability enthusiast, lots of my work at Diversity and Ability focusses around making software and the web accessible and usable. I think coding is fun and rewarding and that more people should do it. I work with an educational trust to deliver programming courses to 16-18 year-olds. In my spare time I like to code, I also enjoy wood turning, cooking, and the occasional video game.

Experience

BAFTA 2014 to present Software Engineer I help build and grow BAFTA's commercial offerings. This includes digital media distribution platforms, awards services, and copyright tools.

The Media Institute 2014 to 2015 Software Engineer I worked on several Innovate UK projects looking to expand the cutting edge of digital tools in the media industry. I also helped to build, run, and analyse several large-scale Amazon Mechanical Turk user studies.

Diversity and Ability 2009 to present Associate Director, Head of IT

I setup, run, and maintain the internal IT provision for Diversity and Ability. I also work as their sole web developer; managing their entire web ecosystem.

Freelance 2009 to present Software Engineer, Web Developer I have built many websites and software projects. Details of the open source ones can be found on my <u>GitHub page</u>.

MRes Dissertation 2012

Researcher

I worked on improving the reliability of the BitTorrent protocol by fully decentralising the peer discovery mechanisms. Paper published in IEEE P2P2013.

BSc Dissertation 2011 Software Engineer I built a collaborative, real-time, cloud-based IDE using Google Wave technology.

Education

Certificate in Data Protection 2016

The British Computer Society

MRes Crime and Security Science 2011 to 2012 University College London, UK

BSc Computer Science 2008 to 2011 University College London, UK

References

Ingemar Cox Director of Research

Computer Science Department, University College London

Atif Choudhury CEO Diversity and Ability